<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Petrified Voices</title>
    <description>Petra's personal research on why people created thousands messages written into stone and what can we learn from them
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 14:44:52 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 14:44:52 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Updating...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, folks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page is undergoing a much needed update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay tuned for more.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 14:43:59 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/random/2022/05/31/Updating.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/random/2022/05/31/Updating.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Random</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Finally doing some research / exploration</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, fellow epigraphers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am have finally got a little time to play with digital datasets and try some of the visualisations. I am hoping to make more detailed post on the technology behind the lovely maps but in short version:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are using dataset from the Epigraphic Database Heidelberg, hencefort known as EDH, as our core dataset (for testing and scoping).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We have decided to use EDH mostly because it has clearly stated licence and it has provided an API to access the data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are using custom made scipts in Python via Google Colab to access the API, download the data (Thanks to hard work of my colleague Vojtech Kase)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are using additional custom Python scripts to interrogate the data based on the current research questions, such as in my case were the milestones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My aim was to access the information about all milestones in the EDH database, plot them on the map with relation to the known Roman roads as published and digitized by the Barrington Atlas (BA).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was puzzled by the following questions for a long time and hopefully I am now closer to finding a satisfactory answer to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Were the milestones placed mostly around major roads?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Were the milestones distributed equally through space and time?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the language of a milestone change from Latin to Greek as we progress eastward?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where were the most milestones placed at - the liminal provinces where the army was constanly on the move, or rather more central provinces where the roads were used mostly by non-military inhabitants?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the time where most milestones where created corresponds with periods of military unrest, building activities, or periods of peace?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course the answer depends on the nature of the dataset (EDH), but I am hoping we would be able to get our hands on more datasets to enrich the credibility of the answer. The more data, the more credible image of the ancient historical reality (one would hope).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a simple visualisation of the dataset made Carto.com. Feel free to play with the data, ask me questions. Or reuse (under the CC Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International license).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;150%&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; frameborder=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;https://petrajanouchova.carto.com/builder/3628ea38-a036-495b-8795-d36137f2b31e/embed&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&amp;gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/research/2019/12/18/Milestones.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/research/2019/12/18/Milestones.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Research</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello from Aarhus University</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, folks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since I have posted anything. As usual, there has been quite a development in the past few months. I got married and changed my last name from &lt;strong&gt;Janouchová&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;Heřmánková&lt;/strong&gt;, so if you haven’t recognized the name at first, you are not the only one confused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for the news no. 2, I have been offred and accepted a Postdoc position at Aarhus University in Denmark! Yay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;image-link&quot; href=&quot;/assets/Aarhus_start.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;Gallery-1&quot; data-title=&quot;Petra in her new office at Aarhus University&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/Aarhus_start.jpg&quot; /&gt;Petra settling down in her new office at Aarhus University, Denmark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next few days I will be posting more about the team and the project we all be working on for the next three years!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2019/09/04/Hello_Aarhus.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2019/09/04/Hello_Aarhus.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Test post</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, folks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my first post on this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be posting irregularly my insights about epigraphy and the digital world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay tuned for more.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 14:43:59 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/random/2019/04/01/Test_post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/random/2019/04/01/Test_post.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Random</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
